# **DREW BAKER**

# Software Engineer

## CONTACT

- **6**62.202.8802
- drew.baker.97@gmail.com
- www.PastTenseDraw.com
- Frisco, TX

#### **EDUCATION**



- B.S. Computer Science
- GPA: 4.0 / 4.0
- Fall, 2019

# **PROFICIENCIES**

- Python Java
- Javascript
  Angular
- D3 SQL
- AWS CSS
- Git QT
- DataDoxygenVisualization
- GUI Design Leadership

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- AWS Solutions Architect Associate
- Certified Secure Software
   Engineer Associate
- Capital One Data Ninja

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a creative, solution-oriented software developer. I'm originally from Oxford, MS, and have a bachelor's in Computer Science from Mississippi State University. Currently, I'm working remotely for Capital One, based out of their North Texas people center. While I thoroughly enjoy a good problem to solve or feature to implement, my true passions are visual and experience design. For me, there's no greater feeling than taking an idea, building on it from the ground up, and refining it into a useful, usable system that users enjoy. Even though my heart lies in the user experience, I've got plenty of experience working in a full-stack capacity as well. Outside of work, you'll probably find me behind a video camera, outdoors with my dog, or watching Mississippi State baseball.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### SENIOR ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Capital One / Plano, TX / March 2021 - Present

Developed features for an in-house data processing system built with Angular on the front end, while providing feedback and design suggestions for the API on the back end. Remediated bugs in existing code while learning the ropes of Angular. Just getting started in this role, more to come soon!

#### ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Capital One / Plano, TX / Feb. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Upgraded and maintained internal analytics site, building data visualizations from the ground up using SQL, Python (Pandas), and D3.js. Quickly shifted from a contributor role to making strategic decisions regarding process and upgrades, increasing monitoring and analytics capabilities by over 100%. Overhauled site architecture to create resiliency standards and implemented a custom Slack notification system.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - CLEARANCE: SECRET

Dynetics, Inc. / Huntsville, AL / May 2019 - Aug. 2019

Designed and implemented dynamic GUI with Qt for C++, following development lifecycle from planning to deployment. Converted scripts from Perl to Python for use in other applications. Implemented command line interface from source code of FOX toolkit GUI application. Created and packaged responsive flare model renderer.

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CO-OP**

Camgian Microsystems / Starkville, MS / May 2017 - May 2019

Worked with senior engineers and head of quality assurance to write thousands of software tests, patch hundreds of various bugs, and clean up all repositories. Extensively documented various products to be used by customers in the field. Created and enforced standards for Java code.

## **GRAPHIC / MOTION DESIGN INTERN**

Hail State Productions / Starkville, MS / Aug. 2015 - Dec. 2019

Trained team of 15 students, while collaborating with producers and assistant athletic directors to create video and motion graphic content featured across Mississippi State University Athletics. Designed all graphics for cinematic content and social media.

## **LEADERSHIP**

## TECHNOLOGY DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM SUPPORT COMMITTEE

Capital One / July 2020 - Present

Served other TDP associates by assisting with events, connecting new hires with TDP "buddies", and improving general diversity, inclusion, and belonging efforts in the program.

## **DIRECTOR OF MARKETING**

Mississippi State University Student Association / Feb. 2017 - May 2018

Directed team of 8 designers, photographers, and videographers to creatively market Student Association offerings to all 20,000+ students enrolled at Mississippi State.

# **SENATOR - COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING**

Mississippi State University Student Association / 2016 - 2017, 2018 - 2019

Represented Bagley College of Engineering for two terms. Led Academic Affairs Committee as Chairman from 2018 - 2019. Worked with faculty through compromise to reform numerous Academic Operating Policies to better serve student body.